<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<pc version="5">
<character><version>38</version><uid>1059</uid><name>Johny</name><race><name>Tiefling</name><age>15</age><height>160</height><weight>60</weight><eyes>Green</eyes><feat><name>Languages</name><text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Infernal.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Darkvision</name><text>Thanks to your infernal heritage, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can’t discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Hellish Resistance</name><text>You have resistance to fire damage.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Infernal Legacy</name><text>You know the thaumaturgy cantrip. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the hellish rebuke spell as a 2nd level spell once with this trait and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. When you reach 5th level, you can cast the darkness spell once with this trait and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><mod><category>1</category><type>3</type><value>1</value></mod><mod><category>1</category><type>5</type><value>2</value></mod><spellAbility>5</spellAbility></race><class><id>1006</id><name>Wizard</name><level>7</level><hdCurrent>3</hdCurrent><wealth>4d4x10</wealth><proficiency>4</proficiency><proficiency>109</proficiency><proficiency>3</proficiency><proficiency>102</proficiency><numClassSkills>2</numClassSkills><armor>None</armor><weapons>Daggers, darts, slings, quarterstaffs, light crossbows</weapons><tools>None</tools><slots>4,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><slotsCurrent>4,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0,</slotsCurrent><feat><name>Spellcasting</name><text>As a student of Arcane Magic, you have a Spellbook containing Spells that show the first glimmerings of your true power.
    Cantrips. At 1st Level, you know three Cantrips of your choice from the Wizard spell list. You learn additional Wizard Cantrips of your choice at higher levels, as shown in the Cantrips Known column of the Wizard table.
    Spellbook. At 1st Level, you have a Spellbook containing six 1st-level Wizard Spells of your choice. Your Spellbook is the repository of the Wizard Spells you know, except your Cantrips, which are fixed in your mind.
    Preparing and Casting Spells. The Wizard table shows how many Spell Slots you have to cast your Spells of 1st Level and higher. To cast one of these Spells, you must expend a slot of the spell&#39;s level or higher. You regain all expended Spell Slots when you finish a Long Rest.
    You prepare the list of Wizard Spells that are available for you to cast. To do so, choose a number of Wizard Spells from your Spellbook equal to your Intelligence modifier + your Wizard level (minimum of one spell). The Spells must be of a level for which you have Spell Slots.
    For example, if you&#39;re a 3rd-level Wizard, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level Spell Slots. With an Intelligence of 16, your list of prepared Spells can include six Spells of 1st or 2nd Level, in any combination, chosen from your Spellbook. If you prepare the 1st-level spell Magic Missile, you can cast it using a 1st-level or a 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn&#39;t remove it from your list of prepared Spells.
    You can change your list of prepared Spells when you finish a Long Rest. Preparing a new list of Wizard Spells requires time spent studying your Spellbook and memorizing the incantations and gestures you must make to cast the spell: at least 1 minute per Spell Level for each spell on your list.
    Spellcasting Ability. Intelligence is your Spellcasting Ability for your Wizard Spells, since you learn your Spells through dedicated study and memorization. You use your Intelligence whenever a spell refers to your Spellcasting Ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a Wizard spell you cast and when Making an Attack roll with one.
    Ritual Casting. You can cast a Wizard spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell in your Spellbook. You don&#39;t need to have the spell prepared.
    Spellcasting Focus. You can use an arcane focus as a Spellcasting focus for your Wizard Spells.
    Learning Spells of 1st Level and Higher. Each time you gain a Wizard level, you can add two Wizard Spells of your choice to your Spellbook for free. Each of these Spells must be of a level for which you have Spell Slots, as shown on the Wizard table. On your Adventures, you might find other Spells that you can add to your Spellbook (see “Your Spellbook”).</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Arcane Recovery</name><text>You have learned to regain some of your magical energy by studying your spellbook. Once per day when you finish a short rest, you can choose expended spell slots to recover. The spell slots can have a combined level that is equal to or less than half your wizard level (rounded up), and none of the slots can be 6th level or higher.
    For example, if you’re a 4th-level wizard, you can recover up to two levels worth of spell slots.
    You can recover either a 2nd-level spell slot or two 1st-level spell slots.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Arcane Tradition</name><text>When you reach 2nd level, you choose an arcane tradition, shaping your practice of magic through one of eight schools: Abjuration, Conjuration, Divination, Enchantment, Evocation, Illusion, Necromancy, or Transmutation, all detailed at the end of the class description. Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>School of Evocation: Potent Cantrip</name><text>Starting at 6th level, your damaging cantrips affect even creatures that avoid the brunt of the effect. When a creature succeeds on a saving throw against your cantrip, the creature takes half the cantrip&#39;s damage (if any) but suffers no additional effect from the cantrip.</text><expanded>0</expanded><optional>1</optional></feat><mod><name>Ability Score Improvement</name><category>1</category><type>1</type><value>1</value></mod><mod><name>Ability Score Improvement</name><category>1</category><type>4</type><value>1</value></mod><autolevel><slots>3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Spellcasting</name><text>As a student of Arcane Magic, you have a Spellbook containing Spells that show the first glimmerings of your true power.
    Cantrips. At 1st Level, you know three Cantrips of your choice from the Wizard spell list. You learn additional Wizard Cantrips of your choice at higher levels, as shown in the Cantrips Known column of the Wizard table.
    Spellbook. At 1st Level, you have a Spellbook containing six 1st-level Wizard Spells of your choice. Your Spellbook is the repository of the Wizard Spells you know, except your Cantrips, which are fixed in your mind.
    Preparing and Casting Spells. The Wizard table shows how many Spell Slots you have to cast your Spells of 1st Level and higher. To cast one of these Spells, you must expend a slot of the spell&#39;s level or higher. You regain all expended Spell Slots when you finish a Long Rest.
    You prepare the list of Wizard Spells that are available for you to cast. To do so, choose a number of Wizard Spells from your Spellbook equal to your Intelligence modifier + your Wizard level (minimum of one spell). The Spells must be of a level for which you have Spell Slots.
    For example, if you&#39;re a 3rd-level Wizard, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level Spell Slots. With an Intelligence of 16, your list of prepared Spells can include six Spells of 1st or 2nd Level, in any combination, chosen from your Spellbook. If you prepare the 1st-level spell Magic Missile, you can cast it using a 1st-level or a 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn&#39;t remove it from your list of prepared Spells.
    You can change your list of prepared Spells when you finish a Long Rest. Preparing a new list of Wizard Spells requires time spent studying your Spellbook and memorizing the incantations and gestures you must make to cast the spell: at least 1 minute per Spell Level for each spell on your list.
    Spellcasting Ability. Intelligence is your Spellcasting Ability for your Wizard Spells, since you learn your Spells through dedicated study and memorization. You use your Intelligence whenever a spell refers to your Spellcasting Ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a Wizard spell you cast and when Making an Attack roll with one.
    Ritual Casting. You can cast a Wizard spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell in your Spellbook. You don&#39;t need to have the spell prepared.
    Spellcasting Focus. You can use an arcane focus as a Spellcasting focus for your Wizard Spells.
    Learning Spells of 1st Level and Higher. Each time you gain a Wizard level, you can add two Wizard Spells of your choice to your Spellbook for free. Each of these Spells must be of a level for which you have Spell Slots, as shown on the Wizard table. On your Adventures, you might find other Spells that you can add to your Spellbook (see “Your Spellbook”).</text></feat><feat><name>Arcane Recovery</name><text>You have learned to regain some of your magical energy by studying your spellbook. Once per day when you finish a short rest, you can choose expended spell slots to recover. The spell slots can have a combined level that is equal to or less than half your wizard level (rounded up), and none of the slots can be 6th level or higher.
    For example, if you’re a 4th-level wizard, you can recover up to two levels worth of spell slots.
    You can recover either a 2nd-level spell slot or two 1st-level spell slots.</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>2</level><slots>3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Arcane Tradition</name><text>When you reach 2nd level, you choose an arcane tradition, shaping your practice of magic through one of eight schools: Abjuration, Conjuration, Divination, Enchantment, Evocation, Illusion, Necromancy, or Transmutation, all detailed at the end of the class description. Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</text></feat><feat><name>School of Evocation: Evocation Savant</name><text>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy an evocation spell into your spellbook is halved.</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>School of Evocation: Sculpt Spells</name><text>Beginning at 2nd level, you can create pockets of relative safety within the effects of your evocation spells. When you cast an evocation spell that affects other creatures that you can see, you can choose a number of them equal to 1+the spell&#39;s level. The chosen creatures automatically succeed on their saving throws against the spell, and they take no damage if they would normally take half damage on a successful save.</text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>3</level><slots>3,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>4</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><slots>4,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>5</level><slots>4,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>6</level><slots>4,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>School of Evocation: Potent Cantrip</name><text>Starting at 6th level, your damaging cantrips affect even creatures that avoid the brunt of the effect. When a creature succeeds on a saving throw against your cantrip, the creature takes half the cantrip&#39;s damage (if any) but suffers no additional effect from the cantrip.</text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>7</level><slots>4,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>8</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><slots>4,4,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>9</level><slots>4,4,3,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>10</level><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>School of Evocation: Empowered Evocation</name><text>Beginning at 10th level, you can add your Intelligence modifier to the damage roll of any wizard evocation spell you cast</text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>11</level><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>12</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>13</level><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>14</level><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0,</slots><feat><name>School of Evocation: Overchannel</name><text>Starting at 14th level, you can increase the power of your simpler spells. When you cast a wizard spell of 5th level or lower that deals damage, you can deal maximum damage with that spell.
    The first time you do so, you suffer no adverse effect. If you use this feature again before you finish a long rest, you take 2d12 necrotic damage for each level of the spell, immediately after you cast it. Each time you use this feature again before finishing a long rest, the necrotic damage per spell level increases by 1d12. This damage ignores resistance and immunity.</text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>15</level><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>16</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>17</level><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,1,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>18</level><slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,1,1,1,1,</slots><feat><name>Spell Mastery</name><text>At 18th level, you have achieved such mastery over certain spells that you can cast them at will. Choose a 1st-level wizard spell and a 2nd-level wizard spell that are in your spellbook. You can cast those spells at their lowest level without expending a spell slot when you have them prepared. If you want to cast either spell at a higher level, you must expend a spell slot as normal. 
    By spending 8 hours in study, you can exchange one or both of the spells you chose for different spells of the same levels.</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>19</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>20</level><slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,2,1,1,</slots><feat><name>Signature Spells</name><text>When you reach 20th level, you gain mastery over two powerful spells and can cast them with little effort. Choose two 3rd-level wizard spells in your spellbook as your signature spells. You always have these spells prepared, they don’t count against the number of spells you have prepared, and you can cast each of them once at 3rd level without expending a spell slot. When you do so, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.
    If you want to cast either spell at a higher level, you must expend a spell slot as normal.</text></feat></autolevel><spellAbility>3</spellAbility><spell><name>Counterspell</name><school>1</school><level>3</level><time>1 reaction</time><range>60 feet</range><s>1</s><duration>Instantaneous</duration><text>You attempt to interrupt a creature in the process of casting a spell. If the creature is casting a spell of or lower, its spell fails and has no effect. If it is casting a spell of or higher, make an ability check using your spellcasting ability. The DC equals 10+ the spell&#39;s level. On a success, the creature&#39;s spell fails and has no effect.
    At Higher Level. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the interrupted spell has no effect if its level is less than or equal to the level of the spell slot you used.</text><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Warlock</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass></spell><spell><name>Mage Hand</name><school>2</school><time>1 action</time><range>30 feet</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><duration>1 minute</duration><text>A spectral, floating hand appears at a point you choose within range. The hand lasts for the duration or until you dismiss it as an action. The hand vanishes if it is ever more than 30 feet away from you or if you cast this spell again.
    You can use your action to control the hand. You can use the hand to manipulate an object, open an unlocked door or container, stow or retrieve an item from an open container, or pour the contents out of a vial. You can move the hand up to 30 feet each time you use it.
    The hand can’t attack, activate magic items, or carry more than 10 pounds.</text><sclass>Bard</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Warlock</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass></spell><spell><name>Magic Missile</name><school>5</school><level>1</level><time>1 action</time><range>120 feet</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><duration>Instantaneous</duration><text>You create three glowing darts of magical force. Each dart hits a creature of your choice that you can see within range. A dart deals 1d4 + 1 force damage to its target. The darts all strike simultaneously, and you can direct them to hit one creature or several.
    At Higher Levels. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the spell creates one more dart for each slot level above 1st.</text><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass></spell><spell><name>Vampiric Touch</name><school>7</school><level>3</level><time>1 action</time><range>Self</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration><text>The touch of your shadow wreathed hand can siphon life force from others to heal your wounds. Make a melee spell attack against a creature within your reach. On a hit, the target takes 3d6 necrotic damage, and you regain hit points equal to half the amount of necrotic damage dealt. Until the spell ends, you can make the attack again on each of your turns as an action.
    At Higher Levels. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 3rd.</text><sclass>Warlock</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass></spell><spell><name>Misty Step</name><school>2</school><level>2</level><time>1 bonus action</time><range>Self</range><v>1</v><duration>Instantaneous</duration><text>Briefly surrounded by silvery mist, you teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space that you can see.</text><prepared>1</prepared><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Warlock</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass></spell><spell><name>Scorching Ray</name><school>5</school><level>2</level><time>1 action</time><range>120 feet</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><duration>Instantaneous</duration><text>You create three rays of fire and hurl them at targets within range. You can hurl them at one target or several.
    Make a ranged spell attack for each ray. On a hit, the target takes 2d6 fire damage.
    At Higher Levels. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you create one additional ray for each slot level above 2nd.</text><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass></spell><spell><name>Shield</name><school>1</school><level>1</level><time>1 reaction, which you take when you are hit by an attack or targeted by the magic missile spell</time><range>Self</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><duration>1 round</duration><text>An invisible barrier of magical force appears and protects you. Until the start of your next turn, you have a +5 bonus to AC, including against the triggering attack, and you take no damage from magic missile.</text><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass></spell><spell><name>Fire Bolt</name><school>5</school><time>1 action</time><range>120 feet</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><duration>Instantaneous</duration><text>You hurl a mote of fire at a creature or object within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes 1d10 fire damage. A flammable object hit by this spell ignites if it isn&#39;t being worn or carried.
    This spell&#39;s damage increases by 1d10 when you reach 5th level (2d10), 11th level (3d10), and 17th level (4d10).</text><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass></spell><spell><name>Fireball</name><school>5</school><level>3</level><time>1 action</time><range>150 feet</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><m>1</m><materials>a tiny ball of bat guano and sulfur</materials><duration>Instantaneous</duration><text>A bright streak flashes from your pointing finger to a point you choose within range and then blossoms with a low roar into an explosion of flame. Each creature in a 20 foot radius sphere centered on that point must make a Dexterity saving throw. A target takes 8d6 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.
    The fire spreads around corners. It ignites flammable objects in the area that aren’t being worn or carried.
    At Higher Levels. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 3rd.</text><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass></spell><spell><name>Animate Dead</name><school>7</school><level>3</level><time>1 minute</time><range>10 feet</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><m>1</m><materials>a drop of blood, a piece of flesh, and a pinch of bone dust</materials><duration>Instantaneous</duration><text>This spell creates an undead servant. Choose a pile of bones or a corpse of a Medium or Small humanoid within range. Your spell imbues the target with a foul mimicry of life, raising it as an undead creature. The target becomes a skeleton if you chose bones or a zombie if you chose a corpse (the GM has the creature’s game statistics).
    On each of your turns, you can use a bonus action to mentally command any creature you made with this spell if the creature is within 60 feet of you (if you control multiple creatures, you can command any or all of them at the same time, issuing the same command to each one). You decide what action the creature will take and where it will move during its next turn, or you can issue a general command, such as to guard a particular chamber or corridor. If you issue no commands, the creature only defends itself against hostile creatures. Once given an order, the creature continues to follow it until its task is complete.
    The creature is under your control for 24 hours, after which it stops obeying any command you’ve given it. To maintain control of the creature for another 24 hours, you must cast this spell on the creature again before the current 24 hour period ends. This use of the spell reasserts your control over up to four creatures you have animated with this spell, rather than animating a new one.
    At Higher Levels. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, you animate or reassert control over two additional undead creatures for each slot level above 3rd. Each of the creatures must come from a different corpse or pile of bones.</text><sclass>Cleric</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass></spell><spell><name>Resilient Sphere</name><school>5</school><level>4</level><time>1 action</time><range>30 feet</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><m>1</m><materials>a hemispherical piece of clear crystal and a matching hemispherical piece of gum arabic</materials><duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration><text>A sphere of shimmering force encloses a creature or object of Large size or smaller within range. An unwilling creature must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, the creature is enclosed for the duration.
    Nothing—not physical objects, energy, or other spell effects—can pass through the barrier, in or out, though a creature in the sphere can breathe there. The sphere is immune to all damage, and a creature or object inside can’t be damaged by attacks or effects originating from outside, nor can a creature inside the sphere damage anything outside it.
    The sphere is weightless and just large enough to contain the creature or object inside. An enclosed creature can use its action to push against the sphere’s walls and thus roll the sphere at up to half the creature’s speed. Similarly, the globe can be picked up and moved by other creatures.
    A disintegrate spell targeting the globe destroys it without harming anything inside it.</text><sclass>Wizard</sclass></spell><spell><name>Invisibility</name><school>6</school><level>2</level><time>1 action</time><range>Touch</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><m>1</m><materials>an eyelash encased in gum arabic</materials><duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration><text>A creature you touch becomes invisible until the spell ends. Anything the target is wearing or carrying is invisible as long as it is on the target’s person. The spell ends for a target that attacks or casts a spell.
    At Higher Levels. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 2nd.</text><sclass>Bard</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Warlock</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass></spell><spell><name>Illusory Script</name><school>6</school><ritual>1</ritual><level>1</level><time>1 minute</time><range>Touch</range><s>1</s><m>1</m><materials>a lead based ink worth at least 10 gp, which the spell consumes</materials><duration>10 days</duration><text>You write on parchment, paper, or some other suitable writing material and imbue it with a potent illusion that lasts for the duration.
    To you and any creatures you designate when you cast the spell, the writing appears normal, written in your hand, and conveys whatever meaning you intended when you wrote the text. To all others, the writing appears as if it were written in an unknown or magical script that is unintelligible. Alternatively, you can cause the writing to appear to be an entirely different message, written in a different hand and language, though the language must be one you know.
    Should the spell be dispelled, the original script and the illusion both disappear.
    A creature with truesight can read the hidden message.</text><sclass>Bard</sclass><sclass>Warlock</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass></spell><spell><name>Ray of Enfeeblement</name><school>7</school><level>2</level><time>1 action</time><range>60 feet</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration><text>A black beam of enervating energy springs from your finger toward a creature within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target deals only half damage with weapon attacks that use Strength until the spell ends.
    At the end of each of the target’s turns, it can make a Constitution saving throw against the spell. On a success, the spell ends.</text><sclass>Warlock</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass></spell><spell><name>Detect Thoughts</name><school>3</school><level>2</level><time>1 action</time><range>Self</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><m>1</m><materials>a copper piece</materials><duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration><text>For the duration, you can read the thoughts of certain creatures. When you cast the spell and as your action on each turn until the spell ends, you can focus your mind on any one creature that you can see within 30 feet of you. If the creature you choose has an Intelligence of 3 or lower or doesn’t speak any language, the creature is unaffected.
    You initially learn the surface thoughts of the creature—what is most on its mind in that moment. As an action, you can either shift your attention to another creature’s thoughts or attempt to probe deeper into the same creature’s mind. If you probe deeper, the target must make a Wisdom saving throw. If it fails, you gain insight into its reasoning (if any), its emotional state, and something that looms large in its mind (such as something it worries over, loves, or hates). If it succeeds, the spell ends. Either way, the target knows that you are probing into its mind, and unless you shift your attention to another creature’s thoughts, the creature can use its action on its turn to make an Intelligence check contested by your Intelligence check; if it succeeds, the spell ends.
    Questions verbally directed at the target creature naturally shape the course of its thoughts, so this spell is particularly effective as part of an interrogation.
    You can also use this spell to detect the presence of thinking creatures you can’t see. When you cast the spell or as your action during the duration, you can search for thoughts within 30 feet of you. The spell can penetrate barriers, but 2 feet of rock, 2 inches of any metal other than lead, or a thin sheet of lead blocks you. You can’t detect a creature with an Intelligence of 3 or lower or one that doesn’t speak any language.
    Once you detect the presence of a creature in this way, you can read its thoughts for the rest of the duration as described above, even if you can’t see it, but it must still be within range.</text><sclass>Bard</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass></spell><spell><name>False Life</name><school>7</school><level>1</level><time>1 action</time><range>Self</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><m>1</m><materials>a small amount of alcohol or distilled spirits</materials><duration>1 hour</duration><text>Bolstering yourself with a necromantic facsimile of life, you gain 1d4 + 4 temporary hit points for the duration.
    At Higher Levels. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you gain 5 additional temporary hit points for each slot level above 1st.</text><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass></spell><spell><name>Ice Storm</name><school>5</school><level>4</level><time>1 action</time><range>300 feet</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><m>1</m><materials>a pinch of dust and a few drops of water</materials><duration>Instantaneous</duration><text>A hail of rock hard ice pounds to the ground in a 20  foot radius, 40 foot high cylinder centered on a point within range. Each creature in the cylinder must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 2d8 bludgeoning damage and 4d6 cold damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.
    Hailstones turn the storm’s area of effect into difficult terrain until the end of your next turn.
    At Higher Levels. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the bludgeoning damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 4th.</text><sclass>Druid</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass></spell><spell><name>Unseen Servant</name><school>2</school><ritual>1</ritual><level>1</level><time>1 action</time><range>60 feet</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><m>1</m><materials>a piece of string and a bit of wood</materials><duration>1 hour</duration><text>This spell creates an invisible, mindless, shapeless force that performs simple tasks at your command until the spell ends. The servant springs into existence in an unoccupied space on the ground within range. It has AC 10, 1 hit point, and a Strength of 2, and it can’t attack. If it drops to 0 hit points, the spell ends.
    Once on each of your turns as a bonus action, you can mentally command the servant to move up to 15 feet and interact with an object. The servant can perform simple tasks that a human servant could do, such as fetching things, cleaning, mending, folding clothes, lighting fires, serving food, and pouring wine. Once you give the command, the servant performs the task to the best of its ability until it completes the task, then waits for your next command.
    If you command the servant to perform a task that would move it more than 60 feet away from you, the spell ends.</text><sclass>Bard</sclass><sclass>Warlock</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass></spell><spell><name>Minor Illusion</name><school>6</school><time>1 action</time><range>30 feet</range><s>1</s><m>1</m><materials>a bit of fleece</materials><duration>1 minute</duration><text>You create a sound or an image of an object within range that lasts for the duration. The illusion also ends if you dismiss it as an action or cast this spell again.
    If you create a sound, its volume can range from a whisper to a scream. It can be your voice, someone else’s voice, a lion’s roar, a beating of drums, or any other sound you choose. The sound continues unabated throughout the duration, or you can make discrete sounds at different times before the spell ends.
    If you create an image of an object—such as a chair, muddy footprints, or a small chest—it must be no larger than a 5 foot cube. The image can’t create sound, light, smell, or any other sensory effect. Physical interaction with the image reveals it to be an illusion, because things can pass through it.
    If a creature uses its action to examine the sound or image, the creature can determine that it is an illusion with a successful Intelligence (Investigation) check against your spell save DC. If a creature discerns the illusion for what it is, the illusion becomes faint to the creature.</text><sclass>Bard</sclass><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Warlock</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass></spell><spell><name>Chill Touch</name><school>7</school><time>1 action</time><range>120 feet</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><duration>1 round</duration><text>You create a ghostly, skeletal hand in the space of a creature within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the creature to assail it with the chill of the grave. On a hit, the target takes 1d8 necrotic damage, and it can’t regain hit points until the start of your next turn. Until then, the hand clings to the target.
    If you hit an undead target, it also has disadvantage on attack rolls against you until the end of your next turn.
    This spell’s damage increases by 1d8 when you reach 5th level (2d8), 11th level (3d8), and 17th level (4d8).</text><sclass>Sorcerer</sclass><sclass>Warlock</sclass><sclass>Wizard</sclass></spell></class><background><name>Acolyte</name><align>Lawful neutral</align><feat><name>Languages</name><text>Two of your choice.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Equipment</name><text>A holy symbol (a gift to you when you entered the priesthood), a prayer book or prayer wheel, 5 sticks of incense, vestments, a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 15 gp.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Shelter of the Faithful</name><text>As an acolyte, you command the respect of those who share your faith, and you can perform the religious ceremonies of your deity. You and your adventuring companions can expect to receive free healing and care at a temple, shrine, or other established presence of your faith, though you must provide any material components needed for spells. Those who share your religion will support you (but only you) at a modest lifestyle.
    You might also have ties to a specific temple dedicated to your chosen deity or pantheon, and you have a residence there. This could be the temple where you used to serve, if you remain on good terms with it, or a temple where you have found a new home. While near your temple, you can call upon the priests for assistance, provided the assistance you ask for is not hazardous and you remain in good standing with your temple.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><proficiency>114</proficiency><proficiency>106</proficiency></background>
<xp>23400</xp><unarmed>1</unarmed><slots>4,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><slotsCurrent>4,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0,</slotsCurrent><feat><name>Grappler</name><text>You’ve developed the skills necessary to hold your own in close quarters grappling. You gain the following benefits:
• You have advantage on attack rolls against a creature you are grappling.
• You can use your action to try to pin a creature grappled by you. To do so, make another grapple check. If you succeed, you and the creature are both restrained until the grapple ends.</text><expanded>0</expanded><prereq>Strength 13 or higher</prereq></feat><feat><name>Language</name><text>German</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><item><name>Dagger</name><text>Golden inscription</text><type>5</type><quantity>0</quantity><value>2.0</value><weight>1.0</weight><damage1H>1d4</damage1H><damageType>2</damageType><weaponProperty>138</weaponProperty><weaponRange>20</weaponRange><weaponLongRange>60</weaponLongRange><ac>-1</ac><strength>-1</strength><mod><type>1</type></mod></item><item><name>Studded Leather Armor</name><type>1</type><slot>5</slot><value>45.0</value><weight>13.0</weight><ac>12</ac></item><item><name>Gold (gp)</name><type>15</type><quantity>35</quantity><value>1.0</value><weight>0.02</weight><ac>-1</ac><strength>-1</strength></item><item><name>Tissue</name><ac>-1</ac><strength>-1</strength></item><item><name>Zähne</name><text>Human teeth</text><type>14</type><quantity>100</quantity><ac>-1</ac><strength>-1</strength></item><item><name>Blanket</name><quantity>17</quantity><value>0.5</value><weight>6.0</weight><ac>-1</ac><strength>-1</strength></item><item><name>Magnesium</name><weight>0.5</weight><ac>-1</ac><strength>-1</strength></item><item><name>Silver (sp)</name><type>15</type><quantity>50</quantity><value>0.1</value><weight>0.02</weight><ac>-1</ac><strength>-1</strength></item><item><name>Rat Poison</name><slot>1</slot><quantity>6</quantity><ac>-1</ac><strength>-1</strength></item><item><name>Deutscher dienstausweis</name><text>Deutscher dienstausweis</text><value>0.2</value><ac>-1</ac><strength>-1</strength></item><item><name>Deutsche Mark</name><type>15</type><quantity>15000</quantity><ac>-1</ac><strength>-1</strength></item><item><name>Granade</name><text>Explodes
7 feet</text><slot>1</slot><quantity>2</quantity><weight>0.8</weight><ac>-1</ac><strength>-1</strength><roll>12n</roll></item><note><name>Language</name><text>German</text></note><abilities>8,13,10,15,15,10,</abilities><hpMax>30</hpMax><hpCurrent>25</hpCurrent></character></pc>